

R.Vigário Taques Bittencout - Santo Amaro São Paulo - Brazil +55 11 99411-9933 paolo.2frame@gmail.com paoloalmeida.com

## BIO

I'm a(n) UX/Web/Mobile Developer and Designer, who loves to work with creative projects. Currently pushing code at Brasil/CT, and over the years I have worked with awesome companies like Visa, Avon, Disney, Mondelez, Estrela Brinquedos and others. I'm enthusiast about open-source projects, and Creator of Front-End Brasil in Slack. In last years I focused in Web & Mobile apps, solving problems and delivering better experience to user mainly in e-commerces and Native/Web apps. I love collaborative and challenging projects, where I can learn and use new stacks, tools, or just a code improvement.

in linkedin.com/in/paoloalmeida

github.com/paoloalmeida

7

twitter.com/paolo almeida

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### FRONT-END ENGINEER

Brasil/CT | Jan 2015 - Present

- Deveylopment of Web App Dashboard in Angular 4 and Webpack, with REST communication with SCRUM Methodology
- Front-End development of E-commerces based on VTEX Platform for brands like: Avon, Kopenhagen, Disney, Mattel, etc.
- Web Analytics / SEO / Performance Specialist
- Development and Maintenance of OnGoing projects, with Continuous Delivery
- Development and DevOps of Web Apps of large scale with backend in .NET / Rails / Php

# ANDROID DEVELOPER

Brasil/CT | Nov 2016 - Present

- Android Development with Java in Android Studio enviroment
- Development based in MVP
- Development using some libs like: Material Design, Android Support Library, Zendesk SDK, Google Maps, Retrofit, Android Support Library, and others

# FOUNDER / FRONT-END / CREATIVE DESIGN

2Frame | Dec 2006 - Present

- Development of sites in HTML5, CSS3 and JS
- Development of sites, portals and e-commerces based on Wordpress and Magento platforms
- Development of Responsive Sites and Apps, Cross Browser / Device
- SEO and Web Performance Optimization and Analysis
- Analytics Metrics Analysis
- Implementation of Google's API and Social Media.
- Branding
- User Experience Design
- Marketing Advertise

#### FRONT-END ENGINEER

GingaOne | Mar 2014 - Dec 2014

- Development of Web Apps in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript in Rails environment
- Development of Mobile Sites / Responsive Sites, Cross Browser / Device
- Front-end OPS (Build, Deploy, Server Config) of Sites

#### FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Akatus | Dec 2012 - Mar 2014

- Development and maintenance of the Institutional Site based on Wordpress Platform Cross Browser / Device Development and Optimization
- Analytics Metrics and Google Tools
- Optimization of SERP rankings and Web Performance
- Interface with Marketing Advertise and SEM
- Interface with Front-end OPS (Build, Deploy, Server, etc)

#### FRONT-END DEVELOPER - UX/UI DESIGNER

WebTraffic | Oct 2011 - Dec 2012

- Development in HTML5, CSS3 and jQuery for clients like: Estrela Brinquedos, Minds Idiomas, Harley- Davidson, Ecofuturo Institute (Suzano Paper), and others.
- Development based on Wordpress and Magento Platforms.
- Implementation of Google's API and Social Media.
- Development and Creation of Apps and Web Sites Cross Browser / Device and Responsive Design
- Web Interface Design and Marketing for clients like: Minds Idiomas, MMartan, Grupo SHC (JAC Motors

Citroën), Sunward Brasil, and others.

## WEB DESIGNER / FRONT-END DEVELOPER

WsoMa| Nov 2009 - Feb 2010

- Web Interface Design
- Development HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Mobile Optimization
- Some clients served: A Tribuna, DSPA, Poupafarma, etc.

# **EDUCATION**

#### ANALYSIS AND SYSTEMS DEVELOPMENT

Cruzeiro do Sul University | 2017 - Present

### SYSTEMS DEVELOPMENT

ETEC Adolpho Berezin | 2006 - 2007

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

ANDROID I, II e III

Alura Cursos Online

JAVA I, II e III

Alura Curos Online

PROGRAMAÇÃO FRONT-END JS/JQUERY

Caelum

# FEATURED SKILLS

HTML

CSS

Javascript

SASS/LESS

Gulp/Webpack

UX/UI Design

Git

Angular4

Adobe Creative

Responsive Web

Scrum / Kanban

SEO / WPO

### LANGUAGE SKILLS

PORTUGUESE

100%

70%

### **OTHERS SKILLS**

JQuery Progressive Web Apps Cross Browser/Device Java (Android) Project Management Web Analytics Sketch Vagrant Jade / Haml / Slim Agile Wordpress VTEX Magento Usability Bootstrap / Foundation OSX Web Standards MySQL Stylus Jekyll